When you expand your business to an Amazon marketplace outside your home country, you'll need
to understand your importing and exporting obligations as a non-resident seller.
In this
video, we'll go over how you can get started with shipping your products to Canada, either
to an Amazon Fulfillment Center using FBA or directly to the customer.
This would include
working with a logistics provider such as a customs broker or freight forwarder, becoming
a non-resident importer, and preparing a commercial invoice.
This information will be most relevant
to sellers shipping from the US into Canada, but may also help sellers in other countries.
You'll notice through your unified account that your current listings are not automatically
created on both Amazon.
com and Amazon.
ca.
You'll need to add your items to Amazon.
ca
just like you did when you first listed them on Amazon.
com.
For more information on this
process, please watch our Seller university video adding listings to Amazon.
ca and Amazon.
com.
mx.
Once your listings are created in Canada, you'll have to find a way to fulfill your orders,
whether it's by shipping your items to a Fulfillment Center or directly to the customer.
If your business is located outside of Canada, you'll need to become a non-resident importer
or NRI to ensure all deliveries to Canadian residents are delivery duty paid or DDP, and
that you or a broker acts as the importer of record or IOR.
Customs brokers or freight
forwarders can provide further guidance on getting an NRI and registering for a Canadian
business number.
Along with the NRI, you'll need to obtain
a Canadian business number, which has 15 characters, 9 numbers to identify the business,
plus 2 letters and 4 numbers to identify the program and each account.
This must be obtained
prior to the first importation.
If you are collecting tax on your sales in Canada, you
are required to register for goods and services tax or harmonized sales tax in Canada and
remit the amount that is over and above what you originally paid out.
We recommend reaching
out to a tax advisor for all tax related questions.
In the seller central help section, search
for "Canada Tax and Regulatory Considerations" for more details.
Amazon will not act as the
importer of record for any shipment and if you leave this field blank, your shipment
may be refused or returned to you.
The importer of record ensures all shipments have delivery
duties filed and paid and that they are compliant with all local laws and regulations.
The most
common reason shipments are refused is because delivery duties are not paid, so please make
sure to confirm with your carrier to avoid any issues.
Also, there are certain items that
are prohibited or restricted.
Make sure to double check applicable laws and regulations
including health Canada regulations and FBA policies before moving forward.
Once you've chosen a shipping company and are ready to ship your goods, the shipper will
prepare the commercial invoice.
It's critical the commercial invoice is accurate to avoid
delays clearing customs.
If you are shipping to an Amazon fulfillment center, enter the
fulfillment center name in the "in care of" and then the fulfillment center address in
the "ship to address" field.
Include a detailed description of the goods being invoiced including
customs harmonized codes, the number of units, unit values and the total of value of each
product.
For samples or products with no commercial value, you'll still need to state a nominal
or fair market value for customs purposes.
For terms of sale, the shipper or FBA seller
should pay all applicable duty and taxes and will be responsible for clearing customs
before delivery to the Amazon fulfillment center.
Sellers are not authorized to import
goods in Amazon's name or show Amazon as the declarant or importer of record on the
customs entry documentation.
For shipments to Amazon fulfillment centers, include the
Amazon FBA shipment ID that you receive when you create the shipment in Seller Central.
The shipment tracking number can also be an airway bill number if you're using a carrier
such as FedEx or UPS.
You are responsible for determining whether any taxes apply to
your business and accounting for those taxes.
Please consult with the tax advisor to understand
your obligations in Canada.
Now that you're ready to ship into Canada, you should also
be aware of how to handle returns.
When processing an international return for orders, sellers
must use one of the following methods.
One, sellers could provide the customer with a
prepaid return mailing label to have the item returned to an international location or two.
Sellers could provide a local return address in Canada or three.
Sellers could offer a full
refund without requesting the item to be returned.
FBA items that are still in sellable condition
can be returned to FBA and will automatically be back online once they're returned and checked
in.
Items that are defective or otherwise need to be removed from FBA can only be shipped
from an FBA facility to a Canadian address.
If you're based outside of Canada and need
to remove an item from your FBA Canada inventory, be aware that the Amazon.
ca removal service
will only ship to domestic Canadian addresses and is currently unable to return inventory
to an address outside of Canada.
You may want to work with a freight forwarding company to
move your exports out of Canada.
Thank you for joining us.
For more information, search
North America Unified Account in Seller Central Help.
Happy selling!